http://www.natureconservancy.ca/en/legal_notice.html

Donate
Fortune Bay, NL (Photo by Douglas C. Leitch)
www.natureconservancy.ca > Home
Legal Notice
Welcome to the Nature Conservancy of Canada's website.
We’ve designed our website to be useful and informative. We hope we’ve succeeded — and we hope you’ll let us know how we can make it even better.
All we ask in return is that you abide by the User Agreement that follows. Please read them carefully, because when you use our site, you automatically agree to them.
Thanks for visiting!
User Agreement for the Nature Conservancy of Canada Website
The Nature Conservancy of Canada (NCC) either owns the intellectual property rights in the underlying HTML, text, audio clips, video clips and other content that is made available to you on our web site, or has obtained the permission of the owner of the intellectual property in such content to use the content on our website.
You agree not to re-use material from https://www.natureconservancy.ca/ or from any other World Wide Web site operated by NCC. In particular, you agree not to copy, distribute, republish, upload, post, or transmit anything unless you get our written consent first.
There are two exceptions.:
As a member of the general public you may download material onto one computer for your personal, non-commercial use only, provided you don’t delete or change any copyright, trademark, or other proprietary notices.
As a member of the media you may download news releases, photos, and collateral information provided for your use, provided you also don’t delete or change any copyright, trademark, or other proprietary notices, and that you adhere to good business practices regarding the use and reproduction of such material.
But please don’t modify the materials or use them for any other purpose; if you do, you’ll be violating our intellectual-property rights.
Limited LicenseNCC grants to you a limited license to display on your computer, print, download and use the underlying HTML, text, audio clips, video clips and other content that is made available to you on our website, for non-commercial (personal or educational) purposes only, provided that:
(a) you do not modify or misrepresent any such content; and(b) you include with and display on each copy of such content the associated copyright notice and this limited license.
Content authorised for release to media can also be displayed, printed, downloaded and used in keeping with the normal practices governing the release of authorised material by other means.
No other use is permitted.
That means that we retain full and complete title to the software and to all of the associated intellectual-property rights. So you’re not allowed to redistribute or sell the material — or to reverse-engineer, disassemble or otherwise convert it to any other form that people can use. Normal exceptions regarding the reproduction and redistribution of media material would apply.
No rights, other than displays, are granted with respect to NCC trademarks. Any unauthorised use of NCC trademarks is strictly prohibited.
No warrantiesNCC does not warrant the quality, accuracy or completeness of any claims, statements or information on our website. Furthermore, NCC makes no representations about the suitability of any of the information contained on this website for any purpose. Such information is provided “as is” without warranty or condition of any kind. This website may include inaccuracies or typographical errors.
This disclaimer includes (but is not limited to) warranties:
That the material is of any particular level of quality or fit for a particular purpose.
That the functional elements contained in the materials will be uninterrupted or error-free.
That defects will be corrected.
That our sites or the servers that make them available are free of viruses or other harmful components.
In addition to the above, you (and not NCC) assume the entire cost of all necessary servicing, repair, or correction.
Another disclaimerWe sometimes provide access to other World Wide Web sites from our sites. But we don’t endorse or approve any products or information offered at sites you reach through our site. Check the Uniform Resource Locator (URL) address provided in your WWW browser to see if you are still in the NCC site or have moved to another site.
SubmissionsNCC will not accept or consider creative ideas, suggestions or materials other than those it has specifically requested. Accordingly, we ask that you do not send us any such materials. If, despite this request, you do submit material to us:
(1)  All remarks, suggestions, ideas, graphics or other information that you communicate to NCC through this site (other than information we promise to protect under our Privacy Policy), become and remain our property, even if this agreement is later terminated.
This means that...
We don't have to treat any such submission as confidential.
You can’t sue us for using the ideas you submit (including, but not limited to, product or advertising ideas).
If we use them — or anything like them — we don’t have to pay you or anyone else for them.
We will have exclusive ownership of all present and future rights to submissions of every kind. We can use them for any purpose, without compensating you or anyone else for them.  You agree not to assert any ownership right of any kind in your submission (including, but not limited to copyright, trade mark, unfair competition, moral rights or implied contract) and you waive the right to receive any financial or other consideration in connection with such unsolicited submissions including, but not limited to, credit.
(2) You acknowledge that you are responsible for any submission you make — in other words, you acknowledge that you (and not we) have full responsibility for the message, including its legality, reliability, appropriateness, originality, and copyright.
Limitation of liabilityIn no event shall NCC be liable for any damages whatsoever, including special, indirect or consequential damages, arising out of or in connection with the use or performance of information available on this website.
THESE INCLUDE (BUT ARE NOT LIMITED TO) DAMAGES OR INJURY CAUSED BY ANY:
USE OF (OR INABILITY TO USE) THE SITES
USE OF (OR INABILITY TO USE) ANY SITE TO WHICH YOU HYPERLINK FROM OUR SITES
FAILURE OF PERFORMANCE
ERROR
OMISSION
INTERRUPTION
DEFECT
DELAY IN OPERATION OR TRANSMISSION
COMPUTER VIRUS
LINE FAILURE
KEEP IN MIND THAT WE ARE NOT LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES, INCLUDING:
DAMAGES INTENDED TO COMPENSATE SOMEONE DIRECTLY FOR A LOSS OR INJURY;
DAMAGES REASONABLY EXPECTED TO RESULT FROM A LOSS OR INJURY (LEGALLY, “CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES”);
OTHER MISCELLANEOUS DAMAGES AND EXPENSES RESULTING DIRECTLY FROM A LOSS OR INJURY (LEGALLY, “INCIDENTAL DAMAGES”).
FURTHERMORE, WE ARE NOT LIABLE EVEN IF WE’VE BEEN NEGLIGENT OR IF OUR AUTHORIZED REPRESENTATIVE HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES — OR BOTH.
JurisdictionUnless otherwise specified, the materials in our sites are presented to provide information about NCC and its programs.
NCC controls and operates this site from its National Office in Toronto, Ontario, Canada. We in no way imply that the materials on the site are appropriate or available for use outside Canada. If you use our site from locations outside Canada, you are responsible for compliance with any applicable local laws.
Termination of this agreementThis agreement is effective until terminated by either party. You may terminate this agreement at any time, by destroying all materials obtained from all NCC sites, along with all related documentation and all copies and installations.
NCC may terminate this agreement at any time and without notice to you if, in its sole judgement, you breach any term or condition of this agreement. Upon termination, you must destroy all materials.
In addition, by providing material on our website, we do not in any way promise that the materials will remain available to you. And NCC is entitled to terminate all or part of any of its websites at any time, without notice to you.
Miscellaneous points about the Terms and Conditions of this user agreementThese Terms and Conditions, and the agreement they create, shall be governed by and interpreted according to the laws of Canada.
If any provision of this agreement is unlawful, void or unenforceable, it will not affect the validity and enforceability of any remaining provisions.
NCC may modify these Terms and Conditions, and the agreement they create, at any time, simply by updating this posting and without notice to you.
This is the entire agreement regarding all the matters that have been discussed in the preceding paragraphs.
© 2001 The Nature Conservancy of Canada. All rights reserved.
NCC Conflict of Interest Policy
Conflict of Interest Policy
NCC Privacy Policy
This website is owned and operated by the Nature Conservancy of Canada. We recognize that many visitors to our site are concerned about the information they provide to us, and how we treat that information. So we’ve developed a Privacy Policy to address those concerns. We may update the policy from time to time, so please check in occasionally.
NCC recognizes its obligation to its members, supporters and online visitors to adhere to the highest standards of decency, fairness and integrity in all its operations. Likewise, NCC is dedicated to the fundamentals of protecting consumer privacy on the Internet, especially for children.
NCC and Canada’s New Privacy Legislation: Protecting your personal information
NCC respects your privacy. As you may be aware, in an effort to respond to the privacy concerns of Canadians, the federal government enacted the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA). Effective January 1, 2004, PIPEDA and applicable provincial legislation have established certain principles for the collection, use and disclosure of personal information in Canada. As part of our commitment to you, we have adopted a comprehensive privacy policy and appointed a Privacy Officer. If you have any questions about how NCC protects and uses your personal information or for a copy of our privacy policy please contact NCC’s National Office, 245 Eglinton Avenue East, Toronto, ON M4P 3J1, by phone at 1-800-465-0029 or by email at privacy@natureconservancy.ca. It is also available by clicking here.
Information we collect and what we do with itAt our site we don’t collect personally identifiable information from individuals unless they provide it to us voluntarily and knowingly. We do not require this information for customers to obtain access to any of our material. However, in order to participate in some of the programs offered on the NCC website, you may have to provide personal information. If you register in order to use special purpose features of our site, we use the information you supply for the purpose of providing the services you’ve requested. If you specifically agree to follow-up contacts by us or ask to be put on our mailing list when you register, we may also contact you from time to time. You can always change your preference for follow-up contacts just by emailing us at the address listed below. We don’t share any information you give us with anyone outside of NCC.
In the email section of our site, we ask for some personally identifiable information, such as your name and phone number. We use this information only if we need to contact you directly because our attempts to contact you by email were unsuccessful. We don’t use the information internally for other purposes, and we don’t share it with anyone outside of NCC. We don’t use your email address for any purpose other than responding to the message you’ve sent, unless we have your permission.
Important note to kidsBefore providing your name, address, email address, or any other personal information to anyone on the Internet, be sure to ask your parents if it’s ok.
Important note to parentsIn communicating with children, NCC is especially mindful of the need to protect their personal privacy.
We may permit a child to send us an email, or to send a friend an email through our site. We will respond to or deliver the email, but we do not store the names, addresses, or the emails in our operational database. We do not maintain this information and we do not share it with any third parties.
Good industry practice dictates that websites directed to children under 13 are prohibited from conditioning a child’s participation in an activity on the child’s disclosing more information than is reasonably necessary. We comply fully with this requirement.
Upon proper identification, any parent can review any personal information we have collected from their child, if we are still maintaining the information in our operational database. They may also have the information deleted from the database, and refuse to permit further collection or use of their child’s information.
CookiesNCC may use “cookie” technology to obtain non-personal information from its online visitors. Cookies are information files that your web browser places on your computer when you visit a website. Most browsers accept cookies automatically, but can be configured not to accept them or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. We do not extract personal information in this process nor do we provide this information to third parties. We also do not contact you. Cookies allow us to customize your user interface to speed up the navigation process and to make the site experience more efficient. If your browser is configured to reject cookies, you may not be able to use all features of the NCC web site.
Once accepted, a cookie can be stored on your computer by your browser. When you log in, this type of cookie tells us whether you’ve visited us before or are a new visitor. We do use the cookie to help us identify site features, in which you have the greatest interest, so that we can provide more of what you find interesting.
LinksThe NCC websites may contain links to other sites. We make every effort to link only to websites that share our high standards of decency, fairness and integrity. We try our best to ensure that these links are safe for children, but the privacy and data collection practices on any linked websites are entirely separate from NCC and are not covered by this Privacy Policy. Other websites, which may contain material not suitable for children, may also link to the NCC website without our knowledge or consent. NCC has no responsibility for the content, policies or actions of these websites. Children should always check with a parent, guardian or other adult before linking to any new sites.
SecurityNCC has taken steps to make all information received from our online visitors as secure as possible against unauthorised access and use. Personal information provided by customers is kept in our secure database. All information received from our customers is protected by our security measures, which are periodically reviewed. You should keep in mind, however, that no data transmission over the Internet is 100 per cent secure and any information disclosed online can potentially be collected and used by parties other than the intended recipient.
Changes and updates to the Privacy PolicyThe NCC website content and features may be updated, revised, modified and supplemented. NCC reserves the right to change the information, features, policies, disclosures and disclaimers at any time. Changes to this Privacy Policy will be posted on our website. Please check the policy periodically for changes. At the top of the policy we indicate the date of an update to the Privacy Policy. The continued use of the NCC websites following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy will mean you accept those changes.
Changes and access to personal informationNCC visitors and parents of children under age 13 who provide personal information to NCC can correct, update and delete personal information from our database at any time by sending an email to NCC by clicking on the hyperlink “Contact us” located at the bottom of each page of the NCC web sites.
NCC and Canada’s New Privacy Legislation: Protecting your personal information ConsentNCC is in compliance with Canada’s Anti-Spam Legislation (CASL). While electronic messages of which the primary purpose is to raise funds for the charity are exempted from the legislation, we work hard to make sure that NCC’s digital marketing is in line with the industry standard and in compliance with CASL. Whenever we collect your personal information online, you have the option to opt-in or opt-out of receiving commercial electronic messages (CEM) from NCC.  Once you have subscribed to NCC’s electronic communications, you can at any time unsubscribe from them  or select the types  of messages you  are interested to receive. Supporters that opt-out from receiving CEMs from NCC will be unsubscribed upon request. To update your preferences, please follow this link or contact our Supporter Services at 245 Eglinton Avenue East, Toronto, ON M4P 3J1, by phone at 1-800-465-8005 or by email.
Home
Who We Are
What We Do
Where We Work
What You Can Do
Supporter Spotlight
Get our newsletter!
Sign up now
Tweets by @NCC_CNC
In response to various provincial emergency orders, our offices and facilities will be closed for a few weeks.The Nature Conservancy of Canada remains open for business. Please find our contact information below.
Who We Are
Mission and Values
Our Impact
Our Team
Our Partners
Work With Us
Publications
Podcast
245 Eglinton Avenue East,
© 2020 Nature Conservancy of Canada (NCC) | ™ Trademarks owned by The Nature Conservancy of Canada.Charitable Reg. Number: 11924 6544 RR0001
nonprofit software
